<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on As the universe, so the soul</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on As the universe, so the soul</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:32:06 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux kernel module development in Arch Linux based VM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux-legacy-gpio/archlinux-lkm-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:32:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux-legacy-gpio/archlinux-lkm-dev/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Linux kernel module (LKM) development is usually conducted inside a VM to prevent corruption of the dev box. Most of the LKM dev. setup guides are targeting Ubuntu based machine, but I love Arch Linux, and there have sparse resources regarding LKM dev. on Arch Linux based VM. So I would like to make a post discussing this. Specifically, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to make the kernel header that is required for out-of-date (no longer present in Pacman latest database) kernel images.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you want to use legacy Linux GPIO?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux-legacy-gpio/linux-legacy-gpio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:32:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux-legacy-gpio/linux-legacy-gpio/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting kernel 4.8, a new GPIO interface, GPIO character device, replaced the legacy GPIO interface. The cons of the legacy interface are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State not tied to process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concurrent access to sysfs attributes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If process crashes, the GPIOs remain exported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cumbersome API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single sequence of GPIO numbers representing a two-level hierarchy - necessary to calculate the number of the GPIO, numbers not stable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For details, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ostconf.com/system/attachments/files/000/001/532/original/Linux_Piter_2018_-_New_GPIO_interface_for_linux_userspace.pdf&#34;&gt;maintainer&amp;rsquo;s slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is still plenty of old kernel users relying on the legacy GPIO.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
